Fire!
Switch after you've fired!
Hurry, everyone!
Ninjas!
There are enemies everywhere!
We just have to keep running.
But it's pitch black in these mountains.
If we can make it to Wakasa, the enemy will give up.
Hang in there!
If you say so, brother, I think we might just survive.
That's right.
If we make it back, Nobuna, Katsuie, and Nagahide,
the prettiest girls in the Oda Clan,
will be there to greet us with radiant smiles!
Our boss's smile is enough for us.
Small breasts are better than big ones.
Girls who never get older are better than pretty ones!
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Eleven
The Retreat at Kanegasaki
Kill them all!
Sagara, sir, we'll protect you!
Hasshi, take our brother and get out of here!
General, we're leaving.
But...
The Oda Clan's monkey.
If it weren't for the castle you built at Sunomata, I would have...
I will never forgive Oda Nobuna or her monkey!
H-Hasshi!
I won't let go even when I'm dead.
General, get out of here...
While you can...
I can't leave y—
Go!
Come on!
Wait!
Hasshi!
Boss...
A man like you is wasted on the Oda Clan.
You may keep that spear as a reward for your valiance.
Mr. Yoshiharu...
Brother, come home safe.
How many survived?
A few Owari soldiers are still fighting,
but it was such a mess back there.
Damn.
We have to go save—
Wait!
If you go back, you'll be killed!
But...!
They stayed of their own free will...
to protect you, General.
The Magara sisters have done splendidly.
The enemy's rear guard is crumbling.
Some flowers only bloom on the battlefield.
I hope to make the Oda princess bloom in my arms.
I guess we were too late to the battle.
Nobuna has already withdrawn.
All that's left is a force of 500 led by Sagara Yoshiharu.
Oda's monkey?
Nagamasa was impressed by him, but...
All forces attack!
The glory of killing Sagara Yoshiharu belongs to the Asai Clan!
Miss Mitsuhide?
There really is no way Mister Monkey will survive on his own.
I don't think so either, but...
I'm going to save Yoshiharu.
I won't let you go alone!
I can't run away by myself!
Where is Sagara Yoshiharu?!
Find him!
Don't let the Asai get him first!
We will take the enemy general's life!
Watch out!
Rokurouta!
Why?
The enemy is after you.
To win a war, you slay the enemy general.
Especially if that general is the hero of Sunomata.
The bounty on your head is probably worth a fortune.
I'm not worth anything!
A bounty, huh?
I suppose we could kill Sagara ourselves.
I see.
We certainly can't let him escape now.
I'm not going anywhere!
I'm going to stay here with my
comrades and fight to the death!
I'm sure that corpse there is glad to hear that.
The man he sacrificed his life to protect
has chosen to die like a dog.
Oda Nobuna wanted to say what you just have.
However, she chose to live.
Nobuna is needed...
by the country, by everyone.
But I'm...
Then it doesn't matter if you die?
What would you have me do?
The question is what you'll use your life for.
Can you die for your companions?
I don't want to die...
but I can't stand leaving
them behind and running!
I'm a greedy person!
I want to have everything!
In that case... just die here.
What the...?
Monkey of the Oda Clan... come out!
Damn it!
We're going to scatter and run.
What are you talking about?
We were order to protect you by the bos—
We need to do it to survive!
If we stay together, we'll be wiped out!
Don't die, brother.
Yeah!
The princess is back?
Is she okay?
U-Um...
Don't tell anyone what you see here.
This is the end.
You're only after me, right?
My men, can you let them go?
Please!
A samurai can at least listen to
somebody's last request, can't they?
Very well.
They are all worth far more than you.
Thanks, masked man.
I will speak to Yoshikage about your soldiers.
You can die with no regrets.
Mister Monkey!
It would be humiliating to have your life taken by the enemy.
Mr. Hanzou!
You!
Farewell, Sagara Yoshiharu.
Yoshiharu!
M-Monkey...
Miss Mitsuhide!
Juubei!
Mr... Sagara.
Princess.
She survived, but...
That's good.
But what about Brother?
Isn't that... his?
She took off her armor, but she still had this with her.
The bullet struck it and lost most of its momentum.
Monkey...
Even in death, he protected the princess!
He's dead?!
The princess...
The princess abandoned him?!
Run...
Run, Monkey.
She's talking in her sleep.
She's been calling his name the whole time.
Don't die, Monkey.
Princess...
My sister is critically injured?
The guards were talking about it.
She was shot and may not survive the night.
No...
Sister...
Let me out!
Somebody let me out!
Well done.
She should have died instantly.
How?
How is she still alive?
Does Oda Nobuna have divine protection?
She's as good as dead.
I don't understand.
He won't be of any use to us anymore.
It doesn't matter.
He's played his part.
The Asakura-Asai force marched through Kanegasaki, 35,000 strong, and headed for Kyo.
The Oda forces, led by Shibata Katsuie, met them with an army of 15,000,
and the two forces faced off in Sakamoto, near Hiei Mountain.
If the enemy broke through, Kyo would be lost.
The Oda forces were in grave peril
without the aid of their leader, Nobuna.
What did you say?!
Yoshiharu was blown apart?
Brother! Brother!
Why would Hattori Hanzou do such a thing?
Bring Hanzou here!
I want—
He has most likely returned to
Mikawa with Motoyasu by now.
The Oda forces have suffered a great loss.
For now, the issue is the princess.
If she learns that Sagara Yoshiharu died,
she'll lose the strength to live.
Do you know anything about medicine?
Can't you save her somehow?
An illness of the heart...
is beyond the reach of medicine.
Princess...
There's one other way, and it's not easy.
We'll have to have her accept
Sagara Yoshiharu's death...
on her own.
If you do that...
She may never wake again.
It's a gamble.
Do you swear to love her forever?
I do.
Monkey! You're safe?
Hey, now.
Don't space out during our wedding ceremony.
Oda Nobuna,
do you swear to take Sagara Yoshiharu as your husband,
and love him for the rest of your days?
Everyone...
This can't be happening.
Mother?
I see.
This is a dream.
Do you swear to love him?
If it's just a dream...
Yes, I do!
Then you may kiss the bride.
It's been a long time.
It's finally time for you to give me my reward.
Yes, the prettiest girl in Japan.
Sorry it took so long.
Nobuna...
Yoshiharu...
Monkey?
Where are you?
Monkey!
He's dead.
I knew it. Of course he is.
This is reality.
I'm sorry, Monkey.
Monkey...
Princess!
I believed that you'd wake.
I'm so glad.
My head's all fuzzy.
I used my medicine to connect dream and reality.
Princess, you're still hurt.
You must lie down.
Monkey's dead, isn't he?
He's dead, right?
He was blown apart by a bomb.
They couldn't even find a body.
I'm sorry, Princess.
I couldn't save Yoshiharu.
That's right...
I can't see him anymore, can I?
Akechi Mitsuhide was also killed.
Juubei, too?
It was a noble sacrifice.
For their sakes, you must unite Japan.
Unite Japan...
The enemies who would stand in your way are still strong.
The ones who took them from you...
Will you let them get away with that?
Of course not.
That's right.
You must take revenge.
I must take revenge for them.
What were you thinking, Danjo?
Lord Nobuna needs something to keep her going.
Something to give her strength, besides Sagara Yoshiharu.
But even so...
In that respect, rage is the greatest power of all.
Now she's certain to unite Japan.
Inuchiyo, go find our strategist.
This feels terrible.
Three points.
Trouble!
Oda's forces have burnt down Tennoujiya.
And they say the princess ordered it!
Miss Nobuna did?
Sakai is supposed to be off limits to all the counts.
What's happened to her?
They've lost their minds.
Without Nobuna, the Oda army is...
O-Oda Nobuna!
We're here to avenge Monkey and Juubei!
Kill every last one of them!
That's definitely Oda Nobuna!
My lord, the order to attack!
We can't possibly win!
Flee to Oumi!
Retreat!
What shall we do?
This is how I like it.
Send all forces to Hiei Mountain.
We're going to let them besiege us?
Don't worry.
This is all part of my plan to make Nobuna mine.
Konoe and Tsuda have fled to Hiei Mountain,
along with the Asakura forces.
We won't let them escape.
Our forces have completely surrounded Hiei Mountain.
Let's attack immediately.
Of course.
Princess!
Hiei Mountain is a center of the people's faith!
If we attack it, the people will turn against us.
I've made my decision.
Please reconsider!
If the people turn against us,
then what have we fought for?!
Monkey is dead!
So is Juubei!
Doesn't that bother you?!
Making military decisions based on hatred?
Zero points.
If we don't fight for the people of Japan,
they won't fight for us!
Princess!
Please, Princess!
As I thought, they're not willing to attack this place.
If we stay here, we'll soon be completely surrounded.
Tsuda, actually...
It's fine.
Let us have Tsuda be our messenger of peace.
Peace?
Me?
Buy time.
You've got guts to show your face here, Tsuda Soukyuu.
Advisor Konoe has sent me with a letter
and gift, as an envoy of peace.
It's too late for that.
This is heavy.
What did they send?
What?
Did you like my gift, Oda Nobuna?
I'm told your own monkey didn't leave a body behind.
All this happened because a country
girl refused to know her place.
This is the least I can do.
Take this head and return to the countryside.
If you don't change your ways, more will die needlessly.
I will take your head, those of your retainers, and your family's.
He won't get away with this!
Princess!
What are you doing?!
They didn't tell me anything!
Wait! Princess!
Princess!
After me!
We'll follow the princess!
An attack!
The princess has attacked!
How could this happen?
Was this your plan?
It's all for her own good.
Messengers!
All forces are to attack!
But don't attack independently.
Work together with the other squads!
Yes, sir!
Do we have no choice?
One point.
I won't forgive them.
I'll never forgive them.
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Final Episode
Conquest